phds.org 2013-05-25

# Privacy Policy - PhD'S.org

## PhDs.org Privacy Policy and Statement

PhDs.org is committed to protecting the privacy of its Users, and we strive to provide a safe, secure user experience. This Privacy Statement sets forth the online data collection and usage policies and practices that apply to this and other web sites operated by PhDs.org. It does not apply to information we collect in any other fashion. 

By clicking the “Accept” button during registration or by using this site, you explicitly accept, without limitation or qualification, of the collection, use and transfer of the personal information provided by you in the manner described in this Statement. Please read this Statement carefully as it affects your rights and liabilities under law. If you disagree with the way we collect and process personal information collected on the Web site, we recommend that you do not use it. 

PhDs.org, jobs.PhDs.org, graduate-school.PhDs.org, and blog.PhDs.org are Web sites (collectively referred to as PhDs.org Sites) that are owned and operated by Collected Insight Inc, a California Corporation. For purposes of the Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy, the PhDs.org Sites and Collected Insight Inc are one in the same and is the sole owner of the information collected on any PhDs.org Site. We collect personally identifiable information from our users at several different points on our web sites. 

## How We Collect and Retain Information

You do not have to give us any personal information in order to perform job searches or to read the content portions of our Site. We collect the following general types of information about you when you visit our Sites: personal information, demographic information, behavioral information, and indirect information. Sometimes we collect combinations of all these types of information. In each case, it is indicated on the web site whether any personal or demographic data must be provided to use the requested service or not. 

Personal information is information that can be used to identify you, or any other individual to whom the information may relate, personally. We do not collect personal information unless you choose to provide it to us. Some examples of personal information that we collect in some areas of our Site, depending on the services you use and local law, are: 

  * Name
  * Address
  * Email address
  * Telephone number

Information about third parties, such as references or contacts, that you provide to us if you have their express written consent to do so 

Demographic information is information that is not unique to you in the sense that it refers to selected population characteristics, such as your ZIP code or postal code, age, preferences, gender, race or ethnicity, occupation, career history, interests and favorites. 

We also collect behavioral information regarding how you use our sites, the areas of our site that you visit, what services you access, and information about your computer hardware and software including your IP address, geolocation, browser and operating system type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is necessary for analyzing the use of resources, troubleshooting problems, preventing fraud, and improving our services. 

## How We Use Information

We use the information we gather on the web site for the purposes of providing our services, responding to any queries you may have, operating and improving the web site, fostering a positive user experience and delivering the products and services that we offer to prospective students, job seekers, and employers. Our services include the display of personalized products, content, and advertising relating to your career experience and interests. By registering with PhDs.org, by managing your profile, or expressly opting in when presented with choices, you have consented for us to use your information, subject to local law, in the following ways: 

  * to allow you to create an account;
  * to contact you about PhDs.org Site updates, informational and service-related communications, including important security updates;
  * to create a profile for you based on information that you have provided to us;
  * to enable you to provide feedback, to contact us and for us to respond to you; to provide information about you and your potential interest in job postings to employer customers; 
  * to provide products and services to employer customers to complete the recruitment and hiring process, such as accessing the searchable resume database;
  * to generate internal reports about the use of our site; and
  * to provide ‘forward to a friend’ features.

Some of our products and services, such as our searchable resume database, enable third parties to see your personal information and to contact you. 

## If You Request Job Alerts

If you request job alerts from us, we ask for your email address as part of the sign up process. We verify your email address by sending you a confirmation link that you must visit to start your alerts. Once you have verified your address, we will send you alerts of new jobs at the interval that you specify. We may use your email address to answer questions that you may send us.

## Job Alert Opt-out

If you no longer wish to receive our job alerts, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each alert or by contacting us via http://jobs.PhDs.org/contact/us 

## About Posting Jobs

Before posting a job on our site, we request your name and email address as part of the sign up process. We verify your email address by sending you a confirmation link that you must visit before signing in. We may use your name and email address to contact you about the status of your job, to answer questions that you may send us, and to inform you of new features of the site. 

## The Tell-A-Friend Referral Service

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. PhDs.org uses this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. 

## When You Create or Post a Resume

When you create or post a resume to any PhDs.org Site, that resume is stored in our searchable resume database in the United States. Resumes in the database will be made available to employers and recruiters who pay for access. Keep in mind that PhDs.org does not verify the identities of these parties. 

## Disclosure of Information to Others

We disclose to third parties within your country and abroad your personal information, combined personal, demographic, behavioral or indirect information, as set forth below. 

  1. We may share your information with third parties who help us in the delivery of our own products and services to you. We disclose information to companies and individuals we employ to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include hosting our web servers, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. These companies and individuals may be located in a country whose data protection legislation is different from your country, and they will have access to your personal information as necessary to perform their functions, but they may not share that information with any other third party or use that data for any other purpose. We will remain the data controller and be responsible for any information shared in this way.

  2. We may disclose such information to third parties if you consent to such disclosure. For example, if you make your resume available, then all parties with access to our searchable resume database (or copies thereof) will have access to that database. If you indicate by configuring your profile that you would like to receive information about the opportunities, products or services of third parties, we supply your contact information to select third parties such as employers, recruiters, data aggregators, marketers or others for the purpose of sending you e-mail or otherwise communicating with you. We use data we have about you (such as the interests and preferences you have expressed) to determine whether you might be interested in the opportunities, products or services of a particular third party.

We also share aggregated anonymous information about visitors to the Sites with PhDs.org’s clients, partners, other Site visitors, and other third parties so that they can understand the kinds of visitors to the Sites and how those visitors use the Sites. We may also aggregate on an anonymous basis data regarding job qualifications, schooling, age, experience level or other information relevant to the job search or competition among job seekers for any such job. Such data may be made available to employers or fellow job seekers or community members.

  3. We disclose information if legally required to do so, if requested to do so by a governmental entity or if we believe in good faith – after considering your privacy interests and other factors – that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (b) protect our rights or property or our affiliated companies; (c) prevent a crime or protect national security; or (d) protect the personal safety of users or the public. Because Collected Insight Inc is a US company and information collected on our Sites is stored in whole or in part in the United States, your information may become subject to U.S. law.

  4. We may disclose and transfer such information to a third party who acquires all or a substantial portion of PhDs.org's business, whether such acquisition is by way of merger, consolidation or purchase of all or a substantial portion of our assets. In addition, in the event PhDs.org becomes the subject of an insolvency proceeding, whether voluntary or involuntary, PhDs.org or its liquidator, administrator, receiver or administrative receiver may sell, license or otherwise dispose of such information in a transaction approved by the court. You will be notified of the sale of all or a substantial portion of our business to a third party by email or through a prominent notice posted on the Sites.

Again, in each of these situations, the recipients of your data may potentially be located in any country in the world. If you are a resident in any EU member state, for example, you must be aware that the EU authorities do not generally consider that the regulations of non-EU countries ensure an adequate or equivalent level of protection as compared to the EU data protection regulations.

## When You Post Your Information to PhDs.org

Please remember that if you post any of your personal information to public areas of PhDs.org, such as in online forums or chat rooms, or in the searchable resume database, such information may be collected and used by others over whom PhDs.org has no control. We cannot control the use made by third parties of information you post or otherwise make available in public areas of any PhDs.org Site. 

## Your Choices About Your Information

Because managing your career is a life-long process, we retain all the information we gather about you in an effort to make your repeat use with us more efficient, practical and relevant until you change or remove your personal data as described below. You may have access to, review, correct, update, change or delete your account profile information or resume at any time. Simply log into your account, go to your profile or resume, and make the necessary changes. You may delete your resume from PhDs.org’s online database at any time by accessing your account. Before providing you with a copy of your personal information or correcting, updating or deleting such information, we reserve the right to verify and authenticate your identity and the personal information to which you have requested access. Access to or correction, updating or deletion of your personal information may be denied or limited by PhDs.org if it would violate another person’s rights and/or as otherwise permitted by applicable law. We will respond to information access requests within 30 days of receipt. If we require additional time to provide access to your information, we will acknowledge receipt of your request within 30 days and promptly supplement our response within the time period required by applicable law. 

If you wish to delete or close your account on jobs.phds.org altogether, [please log in here,](http://www.phds.org/login) click the link entitled “Your Account” at the top of the page, and click the link entitled “Delete your account” at the bottom of the page. Once your account is closed, an email will be sent to you to confirm that your personal information has been deleted (save for an archival copy which is not accessible by you or third parties on the Internet). The archival copy is retained only for as long as PhDs.org reasonably considers necessary for audit and record purposes. We will retain logs, demographic, indirect, and statistical information about you and keep an archival copy of this information in an anonymized form. If your personal information was previously accessed by others using our Sites, we are not able to delete the information or copies thereof from their systems. 

If you are a job seeker with a public resume and have not logged onto the web site for an extended period, we may make your resume unsearchable. If you wish to revoke your consent to our Privacy Statement, you may not be able to use the relevant services and your account and profile information will be deleted. Please contact us by email if you wish to revoke your consent. 

## Posted Information is Searchable

Information you post in public areas of the site or placed in the searchable resume database will be accessed, used, and stored by others around the world, including countries that might not have legislation that guarantees adequate protection with respect to your country of residence. By providing your personal information for inclusion in our database, you acknowledge that you consent to your information being used as described here. While PhDs.org takes measures to safeguard your information from unauthorized access or inappropriate use by third parties, PhDs.org does not control these third parties and we are not responsible for their use of information you post or otherwise make available in public areas of the PhDs.org Sites. Accordingly, you should ensure that you do not post sensitive information to any PhDs.org Site. 

## Other Important Information

## You are Responsible for Your Own Security

You are responsible for ensuring that your log-in credentials (your username and password) are kept confidential. PhDs.org has implemented technical and organizational measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration or disclosure. Notwithstanding such measures, the Internet is an open system and we cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat those measures or use your personal information for improper purposes. Your resume should not contain any sensitive data that you would not want made public. You should be aware that resumes you complete at your current place of work may be monitored by your current employer. 

## Our Sites are Not Intended for Use by Children

PhDs.org Sites are not intended for, nor do we knowingly collect information from, children under the age of 13.

## Our Service-related Announcements

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. 

Generally, you may not opt out of non-promotional email while you remain a registered User. If you do not wish to receive email from us, you have the option to deactivate your account. To deactivate your account [Explain Procedure for Deactivating Account] 

## Customer Service

Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. We will communicate with you by email or telephone, in accordance with your wishes. 

## Service Providers

We use Akismet to provide spam filtering for comments posted on our site. If you post a comment on blog.PhDs.org, we will provide your name and email address as well as the contents of your comment to Akismet as part of their spam testing process. Akismet’s privacy policy can be found at <http://automattic.com/privacy/>

## Log Files

As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information. We use third-party tracking services, Google Analytics and Quantcast, that use cookies to track non-personally identifiable information about visitors to our site in the aggregate such as statistics on site usage and traffic volume. We use this information to improve the Sites and to describe our site’s audience to prospective advertisers. 

## Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We use both session cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session cookie expires when you close you browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. See http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie for more information about cookies. We use persistent cookies to store your user name if you request that we remember you when logging in. We also set a persistent cookie to store your geographical location so that we can set default values in forms on the site that ask for your location. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use areas of our site that require that you be logged in will be limited. 

Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by PhDs.org Sites only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. [See the “Third Party Advertisers” section below for further information.] 

## Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)

Our third party advertising partner, Google AdSense, and our third party statistics provider, Quantcast, employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information. To learn more about our advertising company’s use of clear gifs, please go to http://adsense.google.com and to http://quantcast.com 

## Third Party Advertisers

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website, including Google AdSense, Google AdManager, and DoubleClick. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by Google and/or DoubleClick, visit http://www.google.com/privacy_ads. 

## Links to Other Sites

PhDs.org Sites may contain links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by PhDs.org. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies only to information collected by PhDs.org Sites. 

## Blog Comments/Forums

If you use a web forum or post blog comments on this site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. 

## Access to Personally Identifiable Information

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may update it by logging in to your account or by contacting our customer support by visiting http://www.PhDs.org/contact-info 

## Business Transitions

In the event PhDs.org goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information. 

## Changes in this Privacy Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page. 

## California Residents

A California resident who has provided personal information to a business with whom he/she has established a business relationship for personal, family, or household purposes (“California User”) is entitled to request information about whether the business has disclosed personal information to any third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. In general, if the business has made such a disclosure of personal information, upon receipt of a request by a California customer, the business is required to provide a list of all third parties to whom personal information was disclosed in the preceding calendar year, as well as a list of the categories of personal information that were disclosed. 

However, under the law, a business is not required to provide the above-described lists if the business adopts and discloses to the public (in its privacy policy) a policy of not disclosing customer’s personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes unless the customer first affirmatively agrees to the disclosure, as long as the business maintains and discloses this policy. Rather, the business may comply with the law by notifying the customer of his or her right to prevent disclosure of personal information and providing a cost free means to exercise that right. As stated above, do not share information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes unless you affirmatively agree to such disclosure. If you do ask us to share your information with a third party for its marketing purposes, we will only share information in connection with that specific promotion, as we do not share information with any third party on a continual basis. To prevent disclosure of your personal information for use in direct marketing by a third party, do not opt in to such use when you provide personally identifiable information on one of our sites. Please note that whenever you opt in to receive future communications from a third party, your information will be subject to the third party's privacy policy. If you later decide that you do not want that third party to use your information, you will need to contact the third party directly, as we have no control over how third parties use information. You should always review the privacy policy of any party that collects your information to determine how that entity will handle your information. 

California Users may request further information about our compliance with this law by e-mailing webmaster@phds.org. Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per customer each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this e-mail address. 

## Contact Us

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact us here.
